Nikolay Nezlin

397 W Summerfield Circle, Anaheim, CA 92802
(310) 770 1302 nikolay.nezlin@gmail.com
PERSONAL WEBSITE: https://nikolaynezlin.wixsite.com/website-8

OCEANOGRAPHER / DATA SCIENTIST / PROGRAMMER

Expert programmer with extensive experience analyzing and visualizing complex environmental data. Particular expertise applying extensive knowledge of earth and ocean environments to solve and map complex data scenarios. Strong statistical analysis, programming, and research skills resulting in multiple technical reports, publications and book chapters.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Statistical Analysis / Research
- Scientific / Technical Collaboration
- ArcGIS / Satellite and Aerial Imagery
- Coastal Land and Water / Data Analysis
- Web Tools / HTML / Data Visualizations
- Drone Imagery / Photogrammetry / Pix4D
- Databases / SQL / PostgreSQL
- Spatial / Time Series Analysis
- MATLAB / Python / R / Visual Basic / C++
- Technical Writing / Reporting / Publishing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oceanographer, RBR Ltd.

2019 - present

Analysis of the accuracy of oceanographic sensors, software for data processing.

Scientist, Southern California Coastal Water Research Project (SCCWRP)

2002 - 2018

SCCWRP is a joint powers agency that bridges science, policy and implementation. I was responsible for collaborating with scientific and technical experts on multiple projects studying the impact of stormwater and wastewater. I analyzed scientific data, performed geospatial and statistical analyses, and created visualizations of available physical, chemical, biological and remotely sensed data. I authored and contributed to over 50 scientific publications in peer-reviewed journals and in hoc technical reports for member agencies

Visiting Professor, Researcher and Lecturer - Institute of the Environment, UCLA

2000 - 2009

Analyzed various satellite data studying the effect of 1997-1998 El Niño along the California coast and lectured the course ENV184 "The Basics of Satellite Oceanography" for undergraduate students.

Senior Researcher - P.P. Shirshov Institute of Oceanology, Russian Academy of Sciences

1980 - 2002

Progressively promoted to Senior Researcher with responsibilities for analyzing physical, chemical and biological data collected in different regions of the World Ocean. Participated in 15 marine expeditions (2-4 month excursions) to perform computer analysis and visualizations of collected data.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Biological Oceanography - P.P. Shirshov Institute of Oceanology, Moscow, Russia (1983)

- Specialization: Computer methods of data analysis, Marine phytoplankton
- Dissertation title: Structural and functional characteristics of coastal phytoplankton in the Black Sea

M.S. in Oceanography - P.P. Shirshov Institute of Oceanology, Moscow, Russia (1981)

B.S. in Zoology - Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia (1977)

PUBLICATIONS AND AWARDS

- 75+ research publications in peer-reviewed journals and book chapters
- 20+ technical reports
- Award of the journal "Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science" as a Top Cited Author (2008 2012)